Mairin Chesney

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

09/2014-12/2014

Gooale

Built and launched a tool that allows data centers worldwide to understand historical performance related to repairing data center components.

Software Engineering Intern

05/2013-08/2013

Google

Built a data aggregation tool now used by full-time software and mechanical engineers to correlate relationships between data center components.

Undergraduate Researcher

09/2010-12/2013

BEACON Center for the Study of Evolution in Action Explored the origin of sexual recombination using Avida, an artificial life software platform.

08/2013-12/2013

Software Developer

Student Ambassador

TempoRun

As first hired employee, worked to develop Version 2 of an iOS app that builds exercise playlists based on workout intensity.

03/2011-12/2013

Office for Recruitment and K-12 Outreach

Planned and led events aimed at increasing the number of women in engineering.

Engineering Practicum Intern 05/2012-08/2012

Launched private messaging in Hangouts chat.

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

VEX Robotics Team 08/2010-12/2013

President (08/2013 - 12/2013)

Women in Computing 01/2011-12/2013

President (08/2012 - 05/2013)

Women's Chamber Ensemble 08/2010-05/2013

St. John's Collegiate Ensemble 01/2011-12/2014

08/2010-05/2012 MSU Telecasters

EDUCATION

Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI 2010-2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Bachelor of Arts in Mandarin Chinese

Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China 2014

Chinese Language and Culture Program

PROFILE

Earned a B.S. in Computer Science and B.A. in Mandarin Chinese from Michigan State University.

Used an artificial life software platform to study the evolution of sexual recombination in the BEACON Center for the Study of Evolution in Action. Awarded the Goldwater Scholarship and third place nationally in the ACM Student Research Competition for this work.

Three-time Software Engineering Intern at Google and a Software Developer at TempoRun.

Recipient of the Michigan Council of Women in Technology Scholarship, Von Ehr Scholarship, **Engineering Exceptional and Distinguished** Service Award, and Women in Computing Extra Mile Leadership Award.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python HTML5/CSS3 JavaScript Technical Writing Ruby/Rails Objective-C

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

PHP

Violin Mandarin Chinese Public Speaking Rock Climbing Sailing Photography